# TOMAS MARTIRE URQUIJO



Tel: 0034-654049282

Mail: tomasmartire@hotmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tomasmartire/

Visa: Europe - USA (B1/B2) - Argentina

## **GENERAL MANAGEMENT**

Forward-thinking with over 13 years of experience in both Corporate and Start-Up companies. Fully operational in four languages (English, Spanish, French, Italian) owing to my international upbringing and education.

Excellent communication and interpersonal skills, with the ability to effectively engage with customers, cross-functional teams, and management to achieve sales, productivity and client satisfaction.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Crypto & Blockchain (2021- Present)

**Head of BD** at EXMO.com - Remote (*Cryptocurrency Exchange*) Jun 2023 – **Present** Expand the Exchange offer in terms of listing projects and services throughout Global Markets

International Markets Manager at Gate.io - Remote (*Cryptocurrency Exchange*) Oct 2021 - Jun 2022 Manage a team of 12 persons to growth our presence in EU, Latam and CIS using Marketing and BD techniques

**Head of BD** at Billance.com - Remote (*Cryptocurrency Exchange*) Jun 2022 – Jan 2023 Expand the Exchange offer in terms of listing projects and services throughout EU

# Start Up & Entrepreneurship (2016- Present)

**Head of BD & Expansion at Arxy Meta Labs** - Luxemburg (Saas for Fashion Industry) From 2023 – **Present** Generate a Commercial Strategy to expand the company throughout EU, USA and Asia.

**Consultant at Upcounsel - San Francisco** (*Marketplace for Legal Services B2C for USA Market*) 2021 - Manage a sales team of 5 persons located in Philippines. Objective: Review and change the sales process to increase the quality of the service and the sales rates.

**Country Manager at Alice's Garden - Barcelona** (Furniture *E-Commerce B2C from Decathlon group*) 2018/2020 Manage a Team of 4 persons to open the business in Italy. Year 1 T/O = From 0 to 1 Mln - Year 2 = From 1 Mln to 2 Mln

Managing Director at Aria Gioielli - Milan (*E-Commerce B2C and some retail*) 2016/2021 I founded this jewelry company with 2 partners in 2016. Overall T/O = 350K. Closed during the Covid

# TOMAS MARTIRE URQUIJO

Page Two

# Corporate (From 2009 to 2017)

#### Consultant at Amtrust Financial - United States (Insurance) 2015/2017

Manager: Manage and coordinate the software developers in USA (NYC and Cleveland) in order to build the entire software intranet for the Italian Branch to manage all the processes from issuing a policy until the claim.

#### Consultant at Amtrust Europe - Italy (Insurance) 2015/2017

Project Manager at AmTrust Italia: Change Management, Organization, Commercial strategy definition and Operating Model Design (IT)

#### Associate at Business Class Asia - China (Financial Services) 2014/2015

Capital Investments, Fund Management & Offshore Banking/ Overseas property investment/ Market Strategy & Market Data Analysis/Forecasts/ Private Wealth Management/ High Net Worth Immigration

#### Consultant at Excellence Consulting - Italy and EU (Management Consulting) 2010/2014

Projects: Asset Management Forum 2011/ Banca Fideuram Milano 2012/ Banca Fideuram Roma 2012/ Intesa San Paolo Vita 2012/13/ Barclays Bank Milano/London 2013/ Unicredit Bank Milano April 2014/ Intesa San Paolo Life Milano/Dublin

#### Internship at Accenture - Italy (Management Consulting) 2009

\*All the corporate experience is related to Strategy, Digitalization and Change management

## **EDUCATION**

**2010-2011** Master in Economics and International Politics (MEPIN - Dual Degree) at the Catholic University of the Sacred Heart of Milano/ Master of Science in Economics at the University of Lugano Switzerland

**2006-2010** Bachelor's Degree in Sociology (Economics and the organization of work) University of Milano-Bicocca

**2000-2004** French School of Milan (Lycée Sthendal). Economic Baccalaureate

1995-1999 French School of Bern (Switzerland) and Buenos Aires (Argentina)